# VINEET DUBEY

SOFTWARE ENGINEER | JAVA | SCALA

Back-end developer with 3 years of experience working on enterprise applications as well as an IoT platform.

Expertise in building APIs and server software using Play/Akka and SpringMVC as well as writing unit tests and debugging. Working knowledge of MongoDB, InfluxDB and general RDBMS. Front-end exposure to AngularJS, jQuery. Ability to collaborate efficiently in a team.

# CONTACT



#### Phone

+91 9833 023159



#### **Email**

vineetvdubey@hotmail.com



#### LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/vineetvdubey



# Nationality

Indian



#### sorn

March 6<sup>th</sup>, 1992

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Bachelor of Engineering**

Electronics and Telecommunications University of Mumbai 2012 - 2016

# **CERTIFICATIONS**

- Oracle Certified Professional, JAVA SE6 Programmer
- Oracle SQL Fundamentals I

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# **SOFTWARE ENGINEER |** Enlite Research, Mumbai

May 2018 - Present

#### **Roles:**

- Building REST APIs in Scala, Java + Play for client dashboard
- Improving and expanding the core logic for Enlite's IoT Platform
- Coordinating with the hardware team and setting up 'Design Contracts' to ensure smooth communication between the IoT sensors and the platform
- Coordinating with UI/UX Team to develop/improve APIs for the dashboard
- Responding to technical queries from the sales team/clients
- Setting up infrastructure for client deployments, including but not limited to, setting up the server and bring live the client dashboard site
- Maintenance of internal systems deployed on AWS including the in-house VPN server, Wiki, Bug reporting system etc.

#### **Technologies:**

- Scala, Java, Akka, Play Framework
- MongoDB, InfluxDB, AngularJS, Git

# **ASSOCIATE SYSTEMS ENGINEER |** TATA Consultancy Services, Chennai August 2016 - March 2018

#### Roles

- Worked as web application developer for a US based client
- Operated in an agile environment to deliver high quality software against aggressive schedules
- Worked closely with other team members to plan, design and develop robust solutions based on customer's business requirement
- Developed unit tested and maintainable code by following industry level code quality standards
- Created technical documents/manuals

### **Technologies:**

- Core Java, JavaEE, Servlet, JSP, JQuery, Struts, Spring MVC
- Unit Testing frameworks JUnit, Mockito, PIT Mutation
- Apache Subversion, Maven, SQL